<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.vigneshsharma.in/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.141.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 01:23:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.vigneshsharma.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Courage to Be Disliked</title>
      <link>https://blog.vigneshsharma.in/posts/courage_to_be_disliked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 01:23:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.vigneshsharma.in/posts/courage_to_be_disliked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;courage-to-being-disliked---adlers-psychology&#34;&gt;Courage to being disliked - Adler’s Psychology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;adlers-key-points--&#34;&gt;Adler’s key points -&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Courage-to-being-disliked-Adler-s-Psychology-374a6de5438d4c97b4c9de11c49be71b?pvs=21&#34;&gt;People are not affected by past traumas and emotions, they set out a goal and actively pursue that goal. If you want to change your life, you need to change the end goal.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Courage-to-being-disliked-Adler-s-Psychology-374a6de5438d4c97b4c9de11c49be71b?pvs=21&#34;&gt;Every problem in life is interpersonal problems - that is when you involve others into the equations&lt;/a&gt; .
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the goal of interpersonal relationships is to have a sense of feeling that it is okay to be here. In other words a sense of contribution for the community. A sense of worthiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can achieve this by doing following things -
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separation of tasks - what are my tasks and what are other tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Courage-to-being-disliked-Adler-s-Psychology-374a6de5438d4c97b4c9de11c49be71b?pvs=21&#34;&gt;Life is not a competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Courage-to-being-disliked-Adler-s-Psychology-374a6de5438d4c97b4c9de11c49be71b?pvs=21&#34;&gt;Desire for recognition comes from a sense of lacking mindset, you are craving recognition as an easy fix for feeling worthiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Courage-to-being-disliked-Adler-s-Psychology-374a6de5438d4c97b4c9de11c49be71b?pvs=21&#34;&gt;Always build a horizontal relationships not a hierarchical one - we are equal but not the same&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Courage-to-being-disliked-Adler-s-Psychology-374a6de5438d4c97b4c9de11c49be71b?pvs=21&#34;&gt;Life earnestly in the present moment , here and now !! there is nothing else , no past , no future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Courage-to-being-disliked-Adler-s-Psychology-374a6de5438d4c97b4c9de11c49be71b?pvs=21&#34;&gt;You do not have any other choice than to be courageous and life to its fullest, with mistakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;adlers-psychological-terminologies--&#34;&gt;Adler’s Psychological terminologies -&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Etiology - the present life you are leading is because of these events that happened in your life. it is because of these traumas and events you are feeling like this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theology -  You are not bound by the past experiences, those are just events you are giving meaning to those events  as you see fit. you have decided on a goal  either consciously or unconsciously  and based on that scale you are giving meaning to past events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personalities are lifestyles - you define them and you can change it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kinetic Life - When someone views life as a straight line where the end goal is a destination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Energial Life -  when someone views life as a series of moments , you have to live for each moments , there is no end goal to reach , you live from one moment to another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life lie- ones swifts the blame on others or the environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encouragements is a way of offering help without meddling with other person’s tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pursuit of easy superiority - By being extremely mischevious or naughty you gain a sense of belonging and feeling of worthiness because you gain the attention of teachers and higher authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not bound by the past experiences&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mountain is you</title>
      <link>https://blog.vigneshsharma.in/posts/mountain-is-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 01:23:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.vigneshsharma.in/posts/mountain-is-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mountain-is-you&#34;&gt;Mountain is you&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a book about How we are coming in our own way when we are trying to accomplish something. Self sabotaging our goals in order to not move out of something that is familiar and comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The-Mountain-Is-You-Transforming-Self-Sabotage-Into-Self-Mastery-1200x900.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blog.vigneshsharma.in/images/f3d4c17a-ce10-46d9-a7ee-c56f52a6fb63.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self sabotage is a coping mechanism in order to temporarily relive ourself from our deepest desires and fears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As everything in nature, you need to go through regular cycle of breaking and rebuilding your image, your belief system and your assumptions in order to align with the present situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
